Nils Kottmann

Location: Stockholm / Phone: +46 73 996 81 13 / E-mail: nils.kottmann@gmail.com

I am a data analyst with a passion for finding actionable insights from data sets and communicating clearly through data visualization. I love writing up well-researched reports and fine tuning data visualizations until they succinctly communicate my insights. Experienced in statistical analysis and stakeholder collaboration.

Core Skills

- Languages: German (native), English (professional), Swedish (professional)
- Stakeholder Collaboration: Skilled at working with stakeholders across all levels to understand business needs and deliver data-driven solutions to their problems
- Data analysis: Proficient in statistical analysis, linear and logistic regression, significance testing and modeling as well as report building across several tools
- **Programming**: Experienced in R, SQL, and Python
- **Visualization**: Adepts at creating clear and impactful data visualizations to communicate insights

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: R, SQL, Python
- Data Visualization: R, PowerBI, Tableau
- Other Tools: Git, tidymodels (R framework), Office

Work Experience

Data Analyst at Tre

May 2023 - Present

- Worked across several functional teams ranging from optimizing media spend through geo-lift experiments to analyzing large data sets of customer behavior.
- Primarily using SAS, SQL, R and Python.

Data Analyst at Arla

May 2022 - May 2023

- Supported the Digital & Media team with in-depth analysis to enable fact-based decisions making.
- Created dashboards in PowerBI, using SQL and R for analysis.

Analyst at TV4

May 2019 - May 2022

- Created dashboards and reports blending data from multiple sources to guide decision making in Tableau and Qlik using SQL and R for analysis.
- Worked across functions supporting content producers and TV4's digital services.

Media Management Advisory Senior Analyst at Accenture

April 2015 - May 2019

Managed deliveries for Nordic and international clients.

Education

M.Sc. in International Economics at Stockholm School of Economics

August 2012 - September 2014

- Specialized in econometrics and macroeconomics
- Thesis on the quantitative effect of exchange rate uncertainty on foreign direct investment

B.Sc. In Business and Economics at Jönköping International Business School

August 2009 - June 2012

Major in Economics